tycoelectronics.com 2017-06-28

# TE Connectivity: Every Connection Counts | TE Connectivity

This Privacy Policy applies to the worldwide websites of TE Connectivity Corporation which is part of the TE Connectivity Ltd. family of companies (“TE”), and its global affiliates (together: “TE” or “we”). It explains how we collect, process, share, secure and store personal information (information and data that can be used to identify an individual) of our websites' users. It also describes your choices regarding use, access and correction of your personal information. TE is committed to protecting any personal information that you may provide to us or that we collect during your visit to our websites (“Personal Data”).  

In general, you can visit our websites without telling us who you are or revealing Personal Data, except for your Internet Protocol (“IP”) address. During your visit to our websites, we collect certain information automatically, such as browser, device type, domain, host names, pages viewed and viewing patterns, as well as the country/region where users are located. This information allows us to better determine user needs and interests to drive improvements to website content and functionality, and to enhance the overall customer service experience.  

### Collection, Processing, and Use of Personal Data / Consent

We collect, process and use your Personal Data to the extent necessary primarily for the following purposes:

  *        Website Registration
  *        Request for Information Regarding Product/Service
  *        Website Features and Updates
  *        Product/Service Enhancements and Information
  *        Webinar/Training Registration
  *        Survey Participation
  *        Live Chat Support
  *        Customer Service Support
  *        Job Applications
  *        Product Information Center Support
  *        Sample Requests
  *        Sales Transactions and Support
  *        Participation in Public Forums
  *        Sweepstakes Administration
  *        Customize Account Preferences
  *        Marketing Purposes

Usually, the Personal Data you provide voluntarily will only be used to respond to an inquiry you make or to process your request, e.g. to fulfill a legal obligation or a quasi-legal obligation with you. Personal Data collected from you may include your name, address, telephone, fax number, title/position, company, mailing address or e-mail address, among other information. You may refuse any request for Personal Data. However, if you choose not to provide certain Personal Data, you may not be able to take advantage of certain TE programs and websites features.

When you create an account on this website we ask for your consent to collect, use and process your Personal Data for marketing and advertising purposes, i.e. to contact you by phone or email to inform you about our products and services, offers and news. We also ask for your consent to transfer your Personal Data to TE in the United States and any TE subsidiary or affiliate worldwide, or to third parties acting on our behalf. This is in addition to any other legal ways we use to protect Personal Data in case of international transfer as discussed below You may revoke your consent and ask us to delete your Personal Data as described in the Contacting Us section below.

### Exchange of Personal Data

We share your Personal Data with our distributors, including information we collect via automated data collection tools on our website (see below under “Cookies”), as required to process your orders or instructions, or provide you with information or services related to TE products. We also share Personal Data with service providers for data processing activities such as data storage and analysis.

We contractually require all third parties, including our subsidiaries, to adequately safeguard your Personal Data and not use it for any other purpose than for which it was collected. We will release your Personal Data if you direct us to do so or, if we are required by law. This can be to respond to subpoenas, court orders or legal process or to defend our legal rights. We may also need to respond to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements, or in other limited circumstances permitted by the law (including fraud protection and risk reduction).

We may also share your Personal Data in the event of a sale of all, or a portion of our business, stock, or assets that relate to your Personal Data.

### International Data Transfers

In order to provide adequate protection for the international transfer of Personal Data, besides using data transfer agreements, TE Connectivity complies with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss – U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the European Union and Switzerland to the United States, respectively. TE Connectivity has certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, redress and enforcement.  If there is any conflict between the terms in this privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern.  To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification, please visit <https://www.privacyshield.gov/>.

TE Connectivity is responsible for the processing of Personal Data it receives, under each Privacy Shield Framework, and subsequently transfers to a third party acting as an agent on its behalf. TE Connectivity complies with the Privacy Shield Principles for all onward transfers of personal data from the EU and Switzerland, including the onward transfer liability provisions. TE Connectivity shall remain responsible and liable under the Privacy Shield Principles if its agent processes Personal Data on our behalf in a manner that is inconsistent with the Privacy Shield Principles, unless TE Connectivity proves that it is not responsible for the event giving rise to the damage.

We use automatic data collection tools, including cookies, to obtain information when your web browser accesses the websites. These tools allow us to recognize your computer or other device and your customized preferences when you visit and use our websites. The tools, including web analytics provided by third parties, gather data including but not limited to browser type, IP address, and clickstream patterns (pages viewed and links clicked). You can read more in our [Cookie Policy](http://www.te.com/usa-en/policies-agreements/privacy-policy/cookie-usage.html) including on how to manage your cookie preferences.

We partner with third parties to manage our advertising on other sites. Our third party partners may use cookies or similar technologies in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests. If you wish to opt out of interest-based advertising, click <http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/> or if located in Europe click [here](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/). Please note you will continue to receive generic ads.

TE's websites may contain links to other websites. While we make reasonable efforts to try to link only to websites that share our high standards and respect for privacy, we are not responsible for the content, security, or privacy practices employed by other websites. We encourage you to review the privacy statements posted on all websites you use/access. 

Our websites are not intended for persons under 16 years of age. We do not knowingly solicit or collect personal information from or about children, and we do not knowingly market our products or services to children. If we learn we have collected Personal Data regarding a child under the age of 16, we will remove that Personal Data. 

### Security of Collected Personal Data

TE maintains reasonable physical, electronic, and administrative safeguards to protect your Personal Data from unauthorized or inappropriate access, accidental or intentional manipulation, loss and destruction. Our security procedures are continually enhanced. We restrict access to your Personal Data to those workers who need to know the information to respond to your inquiry or request. Workers who misuse personal information are subject to disciplinary action. However, the security of the internet cannot be guaranteed. If you have any questions about the security of your personal information, you can contact us at [privacyoffice@te.com](mailto:privacyoffice@te.com).

### Data Retention. Accessing, Amending, Storing Your Personal Data and Opt Out Rights

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active, or as needed to provide you services. Upon request TE will provide you with information about whether we hold or process any of your Personal Data. You may review and update the Personal Data that you provide to TE through our websites, or request to have your Personal Data amended, blocked or removed by contacting us as described below. We will respond to your request within a reasonable timeframe. If you request removal of your Personal Data, you understand and agree that residual information may continue to reside in TE's records and archives as far as permitted by law (e.g., for accounting purposes). However, we agree not to use such Personal Data for business purposes.

You may opt out of the collection and processing of your Personal Data at any time as well as from onward transfer of your Personal Data to TE affiliates or third parties by contacting us as described below. We will ask for your prior consent if we would like to use your Personal Data for a materially different purpose than for which it was collected or authorized.

You may sign-up to receive email newsletters from us. You may “unsubscribe” to any online contact from us at any time by following the instructions set forth on the email message, or by contacting us as described below.

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, or would like to opt out or withdraw your consent, please contact us via any of the methods provided below. Please send all questions and comments related to the Privacy Policy to [privacyoffice@te.com](mailto:privacyoffice@te.com).

TE is the data controller for Personal Data we collect via this website. Our address is:

TE Connectivity Corporation  
1050 Westlakes Drive,  
Berwyn, Pennsylvania, 19312  
United States of America

TE Connectivity Germany GmbH is our data protection representative for the European Economic Area and Switzerland. The address is:

TE Connectivity Germany GmbH  
Attn. TE Data Protection Officer  
Pfnorstrasse 1  
Darmstadt 64293  
Germany

TE’s Data Protection Officer can be contacted by post using one of these two addresses or by e-mail via [privacyoffice@te.com](mailto:privacyoffice@te.com).

TE conducts periodic self-assessments to verify that the attestations and assertions it makes about its privacy practices are true and that such privacy practices have been implemented as presented. TE Connectivity will take steps to solve any problems arising out of failure to comply with the Privacy Shield Principles. With regard to Personal Data received or transferred pursuant to the Privacy Shield Frameworks, TE Connectivity is subject to the regulatory enforcement powers of the Federal Trade Commission to investigate claims against TE Connectivity regarding possible unfair or deceptive practices and violations of laws or regulations covering privacy.

### Governing Law and Dispute Settlement

This Privacy Policy and the TE.com Terms of Use shall be governed by and construed in accordance with the laws of the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania, without giving effect to its conflict of laws provisions. You agree to submit to the jurisdiction of the courts located in the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania for the resolution of all disputes and claims and causes of action related to or arising from the Privacy Policy, Terms, and/or your use of the websites.

This clause does not alter or reduce any statutory rights you may have under applicable laws on the protection of Personal Data or, as far as relevant, when you reside in the European Union or in Switzerland, under the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield or under the Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield. In the latter case if you want to assert any of your rights under the EU-U.S.  or the Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield, you may send an email to [privacyoffice@te.com](mailto:privacyoffice@te.com). TE will deal with your complaint promptly but in any case, within 45 days.

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based [third party dispute resolution provider](https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request.) (free of charge).

As an EU-U.S. and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield participant, TE commits to binding arbitration at the request of an individual to address any complaint relating to our privacy policy or the way we process Personal Data that has not been resolved by other recourse and enforcement mechanisms. You may be entitled to invoke binding arbitration when other dispute resolution procedures have been exhausted, as more fully described on the [Privacy Shield website](https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=How-to-Submit-a-Complaint).

Please check this Privacy Policy periodically to inform yourself of any changes. Notice of any material changes to the Privacy Policy will be posted to our websites prior to the changes taking effect. Your continued use of our websites after posting will constitute your acceptance and agreement to be bound by such changes.

June 20, 2017
